One platoon, one valley, one year
Restrepo is a war, documentary film directed by Tim Hetherington.
Directors Hetherington and Junger spend a year with the 2nd Battalion of the United
States Army located in one of Afghanistan's most dangerous valleys.
The documentary provides insight and empathy on how to win the battle through hard work,
deadly gunfights and mutual friendships while the unit must push back the Taliban.
Himself, played by Juan "Doc" Restrepo.
Himself, played by Dan Kearney.
Himself, played by LaMonta Caldwell.
Himself, played by Aron Hijar.
Restrepo is a 2010 American documentary film about the War in Afghanistan directed by British
photojournalist Tim Hetherington and American journalist Sebastian Junger.
It explores the year that Junger and Hetherington spent, on assignment for Vanity Fair, in Afghanistan's Korengal Valley, embedded with
the Second Platoon, B Company, 2nd Battalion, 503rd Infantry Regiment, 173rd Airborne Brigade Combat Team of the U.S.
The Second Platoon is depicted defending the outpost (OP) named after a platoon medic who was killed
earlier in the campaign, PFC Juan Sebastián Restrepo, who was a Colombian-born naturalized U.S.
The directors stated that the film is not a war advocacy documentary, they
simply "wanted to capture the reality of the soldiers."
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
isolation, radio, dead soldier, us army.